VINCENT J. DANG

Email: vincentdang@live.com | Phone: 770.576.5467 | Lawrenceville, GA 30044

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/vincentjdang | GitHub: github.com/vdang1004 | Portfolio: vdang1004.github.io/Portfolio

SUMMARY

User- focused Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Computer Information Systems, Marketing and Design that is experienced in overseeing the build and delivery of complex IT projects. Holds communication in high regard and adept at working with diverse teams to build strong applications and to provide client-centric support.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Coding – GitHub, Heroku, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, NPM, Express.js, Handlebars.js, React.js, Mocha.js, & Chai.js Database – MS SQL Server 2012, MySQL, MongoDB & Firebase

Infrastructure – Windows Server, Active Directory, Cisco Unity, & VMWare

Management - MS Project, MS Visio, Zoho, Trello, Jira, & Confluence

PROJECTS

STACKSoverflow | https://github.com/vdang1004/stacksoverflow | https://young-sea-37961.herokuapp.com

Team Role: React Developer

The STACKSoverflow App, that is targeted to young college students, provides users with tools and information to help them understand basic personal financial management concepts.

- The app contains information and tools to help users become more responsible in basic personal finance. Information interacts with a MongoDB; some information comes from web-scraping.
 - o Tools included: Financial Education page, Savings Goal tool, & an income/expense analyzer.
- Tools/Languages used: Bootstrap, Animate.css, MongoDB, Cheerio, Express, Node, & React

SALUD! | https://github.com/tylerellison16/projectTwo | https://boiling-plateau-32381.herokuapp.com

Team Role: MySQL Back-end Developer

The SALUD! App provides users with drink recipes and snack pairings, contingent upon their recreational selections.

- The app allows users to post and read data for drink recipes in a MySQL database
- Tools/Languages used: Bootstrap, MySQL, Express, Node, & Handlebars

ATLiens | https://github.com/vdang1004/stacksoverflow | https://vdang1004.github.io/GroupProject1/atliens

Team Role: Front-end Developer

The ATLiens app provides information and statistical about Atlanta neighborhoods for users who are interested in moving into an area or who are just curious to what is going on in a particular neighborhood.

- This app contains information and tools to help users obtain a better understanding about certain neighborhoods in metro Atlanta.
- Tools/Languages used: HTML, Bootstrap, JavaScript, & AJAX

EXPERIENCE

Application Support Analyst - Insight Global - Atlanta, GA

05/2018 - 09/2018

Worked with Product Owners, Developers, & IT Support Specialists to troubleshoot complex user issues with Insight Global's proprietary software. Assisted/Escalated issues by determining root causes of user issues. Used database queries to determine code vs. data bugs.

Key Accomplishments:

- Reduced troubleshooting and knowledge transfer time by reformatting and implementing revised Knowledge Base Articles
 & templates for clarity
- Established and implemented new processes for troubleshooting/escalating user issues

VINCENT J. DANG

IT Project Manager - Insight Global - Atlanta, GA

09/2017 - 05/2018

Collaborated with Insight Global's different IT teams to address business needs. Understood, analyzed, and developed schedules of tasks for assigned projects in order to implement IT business solutions.

Key Accomplishments:

- Collaborated with AT&T Project Managers and IG IT Infrastructure team to migrate internet services, from previous provider, for headquarters and 48 other remote locations in the United States.
 - o Reduced spending, by a 20% average, through price negotiation for 3rd party inside wiring services.
 - o Successfully expedited migration by two months due to a change in business needs.
- Collaborated with international 3rd party WordPress web developers and IG Infrastructure team to migrate IG's public facing website, from local servers to 3rd party cloud host

IT Support Specialist II - Insight Global - Atlanta, GA

03/2016 - 09/2017

Provided general hardware/software administration and support for 3rd largest U.S IT staffing firm. Troubleshot/Managed complex support tickets for end users and provided maintenance and administration in different infrastructure systems.

Key Accomplishments:

• 2016 – 3rd and 4th Quarter Top Performance Awards: Customer Service and Quality Resolved Incidents.

IT Support Advisor Intern - Sobo Networks - Atlanta, GA

08/2015 - 11/2015

Provided onsite and remote IT support and advisement for small/medium sized businesses. Troubleshot software and hardware call center support tickets for clients. Provided onsite software and hardware support at client offices. Assisted Senior IT Advisors in server infrastructure audits for existing and potential clients.

Key Accomplishments:

- Improved and implemented revised sales process for potential clients, using a problem/solution-based approach.
 - Provided additional structure for rapport and relationship building.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology: Professional Education, Atlanta, GA – Full Stack Flex Web Development Certificate **Georgia State University**, Atlanta, GA – BBA in Computer Information Systems & Marketing with minor in Sociology